

Pedro Piloto Software Engineer



27/05/1996



Maia, Porto, Portugal



926876686



https://pedropiloto.com



pedro@pedropiloto.com

About me -

I have a degree in Computer Engineering from the Instituto Superior de Engenharia do Porto and I am finishing the master's degree in Software Engineering at the same institution in a post-work regime.

Since I graduated, I have been working as a Full-Stack Software Engineer, but with a special focus on the back-end. I try to deepen my knowledge mainly in technologies like Java, Kotlin, Node.Js, and ReactJS, but also with some experiences with Ruby and Scala in a professional context. Besides that, I consider myself a quick learner and I like to try new technologies to address new challenges.

The thing I most like in Software Engineering is to solve problems, it's an incredible feeling when I deliver something I'm proud of. Also, I'm not a believer of Software as a deliverable but, instead, I see it as an incremental product that must be maintained and monitored.

I'm interested in technological challenges with the potential to create a positive impact on society and my future ambitions are to enrich my knowledge and capacities for productive development of applications of considerable size and application.

Education

2017-2020 MSc Degree in Software Engineering

Instituto Superior de Engenharia do Porto

2014-2017 BSc Degree in Computer Engineering 15v

Instituto Superior de Engenharia do Porto

2011-2014 High School 16.7v

Colégio Novo da Maia

Experience

09/2018 Full Stack Software Engineer

Talkdesk

Part of a full-stack team responsible for maintaining and evolve a system that allows the customization of the customer experience during a call. Participated in a lot of initiatives with different stacks and

teams.

Technologies: Kotlin, Java, Spring Boot, Ruby, NodeJS, OpenFaas,

AWS Lambda, Scala, RabbitMQ, Kafka, Looker, Docker, ReactJS

09/2017-08/2018 Full Stack Trainee

Glintt

Integration into a hospital software module development team.

Technologies: .Net, Wcf, Html, Css, Js, Ts, Mulesoft, Oracle

02/2016 Freelancer Web e Mobile

Development of freelance projects.

Technologies: PHP, Node.js, Html, CSS, Js, Android

03/2017-08/2017 Curricular Internship

FYI

Development of authentication system and shared authorization.

Technologies: PHP, Laravel, Node. Js, Redis, Html, Css, Js

07/2016-09/2016 Summer Internship

Xarevision

Development of communication system and price recognition on la-

bels.

Technologies: PHP, Ionic, OCR, Rabbit MQ, Html, CSS, Js

Projects

07/2017 Node.js Multi Room Chat

Multi Room Chat developed in Node.js and simultaneously was also developed a simple web client for purposes of testing and analysis of ...

its use.

https://github.com/pedropiloto/Node.js-Multi-Room-Chat

06/2017 Check Service

Web application to verify availability and reliability of TCP services, with the possibility of downloading files at the end of each availability test. The tests are fully customizable by parameters. This simple

application was developed using PHP, Html, CSS e Js. https://github.com/pedropiloto/check-service

02/2019 Restaurant Microservices

Restaurant system developed using a microservices oriented archi-

tecture.

https://github.com/pedropiloto/restaurant-microservices

04/2019 Cito - Transplant Center

The project was a system to manage a transplant center. This was

developed as an academical project.

https://bitbucket.org/ajo/labdsoft-2018-g7

06/2019 Rentability Simulator

Rentability Simulator developed using react, meant to be used for

Portugal. It is still under development of new features.

https://github.com/pedropiloto/rentability-simulator

06/2020 Solid Server Microservices

Solid is a project created by Tim Berners-Lee that aims to create new decentralized web paradigm. This project was developed during the master thesis and the main objective was to migrate from a monolith

to a microservices oriented architecture.

https://github.com/pedropiloto/solid-server-microservices

Certificates

08/2017 Certified Scrum Master (CSM) Scrum Alliance

Certification in Scrum Master obtained through the Scopphu training

school and the Scrum Alliance organization.

https://goo.gl/fZvD1x

04/2016 Android Training

Android Training ISEP 30 hours Android training in curricular overtime and development of

British Council

final project for evaluation. https://goo.gl/CxmJDa

07/2014 Level B1 Certificate

Certification level B1 British Council.

https://goo.gl/bF7HV9

Languages

Portuguese Native

English Intermediate

Spanish Basic